<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Google Apps on Chuck McAndrew</title>
    <link>https://chuckmcandrew.com/categories/google-apps/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Google Apps on Chuck McAndrew</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <managingEditor>chuck@chuckmcandrew.com (Chuck McAndrew)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>chuck@chuckmcandrew.com (Chuck McAndrew)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 25 Feb 2017 20:04:41 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://chuckmcandrew.com/categories/google-apps/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Digital Signage on the Cheap – Another Alternative</title>
      <link>https://chuckmcandrew.com/post/2017/02/25/digital-signage-on-the-cheap-another-alternative/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Feb 2017 20:04:41 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>chuck@chuckmcandrew.com (Chuck McAndrew)</author>
      <guid>https://chuckmcandrew.com/post/2017/02/25/digital-signage-on-the-cheap-another-alternative/</guid>
      <description>An alternative to the Chromebit option mentioned in Chuck’s post on the digital signage deployment at his library is a free, open-source solution called Porteus-Kiosk. This (1) OS paired with an (2) old PC or Thin Client, even with minimal hardware specs, (3) a 4GB flash drive, and a (4) monitor, be it a spare computer monitor of a desirable size, or large-screen TV with VGA or HDMI ports, will serve handily as an in-house digital signage solution to promote library events and services.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Prep Workflow For Library Tech Classes</title>
      <link>https://chuckmcandrew.com/post/2017/02/12/prep-workflow-for-library-tech-classes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Feb 2017 00:46:27 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>chuck@chuckmcandrew.com (Chuck McAndrew)</author>
      <guid>https://chuckmcandrew.com/post/2017/02/12/prep-workflow-for-library-tech-classes/</guid>
      <description>It’s a real pleasure to be part of this new blog for “techie” librarians! It’s like having a new library space that’s just waiting to be filled with new books. I look forward to the exchange of ideas that this venue will afford us, and I can’t wait to read about (and also share) tips and tricks, best practices, successes as well as challenges, that we all face as “techie” librarians in our respective libraries!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Digital Signage on the Cheap</title>
      <link>https://chuckmcandrew.com/post/2017/02/08/digital-signage-on-the-cheap/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Feb 2017 20:39:42 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>chuck@chuckmcandrew.com (Chuck McAndrew)</author>
      <guid>https://chuckmcandrew.com/post/2017/02/08/digital-signage-on-the-cheap/</guid>
      <description>Recently, I was tasked with coming up with a digital signage solution for our library. This was for interior displays rather than outdoor signage. We had a few hundred dollars available for this project, but nowhere near enough to buy a commercial solution. Originally, we wanted to run a slideshow for Veteran’s Day, but planned to change it into general purpose advertising for library events after Veteran’s Day was past. Ideally I wanted something that would be very simple to keep up to date.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>